Guide to the Yehuda Amichai Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Yehuda Amichai papers
1929-2007
GEN MSS 572
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
56.77
(102 boxes) + 9 broadsides, 6 cold storage
The Yehuda Amichai Papers consist of correspondence, manuscripts, journals, photographs, printed material, audio-visual and other materials documenting the life and work of Israeli poet Yehuda Amichai.
Amichai, Yehuda, 1924-2000
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Yehuda Amichai Papers were acquired through purchases and gifts from Yehuda and Chana Amichai in 2000 and 2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted Fragile material in boxes 97-109 may be consulted only with the permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies, photographic prints, and digital surrogates have been substituted in the main files for reference use.
Yehuda Amichai's journals for the years 1964 to 1966 and 1993, housed in boxes 95-96, are restricted. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
YEHUDA AMICHAI (1924-2000)
Yehuda Amichai, one of Israel's best known modern poets, was born in Germany in 1924 and immigrated to Palestine in 1936. He served with the Jewish Brigade of the British Army in WWII and with the Palmach in the Arab-Israeli War of 1948 before completing an undergraduate degree in 1955. He taught in secondary schools in Jerusalem for many years and later at a teachers college. He published the first of several poetry collections in 1955, and is the author of essays, children's books, novels, plays, and short stories. Yehuda Amichai was honored with a number of literary awards and nominated for the Nobel Prize for Literature. His work has been translated into over thirty languages.
Summary information on Yehuda Amichai is available in the standard print and online biographical resources.
Scope and Contents
The Yehuda Amichai Papers consist of correspondence, manuscripts, journals, photographs, audio-visual material, printed material, and personal papers documenting the life and work of Israeli poet Yehuda Amichai. The collection spans the years 1929 to 1999, with the bulk of the collection dating from the 1960s to late 1990s.
The collection is especially rich in material documenting Amichai's literary and public life. There are journals and manuscripts documenting Amichai's personal reflections and literary work from the mid 1950s to late 1990s; there are translations of his poetry into numerous languages and critical articles and essays by others about his work; and there are letters, photographs, and various kinds of printed materials documenting his public life in the later decades of his life.
Due to limitations with the technology (Edix) used by the library for describing manuscript collections, Hebrew names and titles have been romanized (transliterated). Special characters in the romanized Hebrew, including the ayin and aleph, have been ommitted temporarily pending changes to the software used by the library to deliver manuscript finding aids.
The collection is housed in 104 boxes and organized into nine series: Correspondence, Writings of Yehuda Amichai, Writings of Others, Journals, Photographs, Printed Material, Audio-Visual Materials, Personal Papers, and 2007 Addition. Boxes 81-104 contain Oversize, Restricted, and Restricted Fragile material.
Series I, Correspondence, housed in boxes 1-14, is organized into two subseries for General Correspondence and Third Party Correspondence.
General Correspondence, housed in boxes 1-13, consists chiefly of single letters and small groups of incoming personal and professional correspondence. The collection features correspondence with writers, editors, translators, publishers, and literary scholars and critics, as well as prominent Israeli and Jewish cultural and political figures. In the 1980s and 1990s Amichai travelled regularly for readings, conferences, and other events, and there is also considerable event-related correspondence with various academic, cultural, and political institutions.
Correspondents in the series include the cultural and political figures Teddy Kollek, Ehud Olmert, Shimon Peres, Yitzhak Rabin, Moshe Safdie, and Zalman Shazar, and the authors David Albahari, John Ashbery, Lynne Reid Banks, Breyten Breytenbach, Paul Celan, Rita Dove, Martin Gregor-Dellin, Patricia Hampl, John Hollander, Ted Hughes, Erica Jong, Patrick Joseph Kavanagh, Naomi Shihab Nye, Cynthia Ozick, Linda Pastan, Anne Sexton, Alan Sillitoe, Marin Sorescu, and others. Israeli authors include Yigal Allon, David Avidan, Amos Oz, Meir Shalev, and Anton Shammas.
The correspondence dates from 1944 to 1999, with the bulk dating from the late 1960s to mid 1990s. Letters are chiefly in Hebrew and English, with some German.
Third Party Correspondence, housed in box 14, consists of all loose third party correspondence. The bulk of these third party letters probably came to Amichai as enclosures and, over time, were separated from the original letters.
Series II, Writings of Yehuda Amichai, housed in boxes 15-36, is organized into nine subseries: Articles and Essays; Children's Books; Forwords and Introductions; Interviews; Novels; Plays; Poetry; Speeches, Lectures, and Addresses; and Other Writings. The majority of the manuscripts are holograph and typescript drafts in Hebrew, with a significant minority in English. Again, because the library's software tool for describing manuscript collections does not support Hebrew characters, titles in Hebrew have been romanized (transliterated). Consequently, romanized titles indicate Hebrew language works. Within each subseries, works have been arranged alphabetically by title.
The Articles and Essays, Forwords and Introductions, and Interviews subseries in the Writings contain a number of drafts and printed versions of short writings in these genres. The interviews, for example, conducted and drafted by others, discuss literature, life in Israel, and Judaism and Jewishness, among other topics, and are a rich source of biographical information. The interviews, which date from 1979 to 1996, provide an almost twenty-year profile of Amichai's attitudes about and perspectives on these and other topics. Writings in these subseries can be found in Hebrew, English, German, and Spanish.
The Children's Books subseries contains multiple drafts in Hebrew of Amichai's major works in this genre, including Sefer ha-laylah ha-gadol (The Big Night Book), ha-Zanav ha-shamen shel Numah (Numa's Fat Tail), and Mah she-karah le-Roni bi-Nyu York (What Happened to Roni in New York).
The Novels subseries includes galley proofs to Lo me akhshav, lo mi-kan ( Not of This Time, Not of This Place ) and holograph drafts and draft fragments, also in Hebrew, of an untitled novel.
Plays includes drafts of the major works, Ninah me-Ashkelon (Nina of Ashkelon) and Le-ehov bi-Yerushalayim (To Love in Jerusalem), and a number of translations into English and other languages. Translations have been placed after the Hebrew manuscripts when both exist.
The Poetry subseries, housed in boxes 20-33, is arranged into four subdivisions: Collections, Individual Poems, Translations, and Adaptations. The subseries features drafts for collections and individual poems, as well as translations from the Hebrew. Amichai's major collections from Me-ahore kol zeh mistater osher gadol ( Behind All This Lies a Great Happiness ) are well represented with multiple drafts of poems. Where translations are also present for particular collections, they have been placed after the original Hebrew manuscripts. Both collections and individual poems are arranged alphabetically by title.
The Translation section consists chiefly of translations of Amichai's work by others, though translations by Amichai, from Hebrew into English, can also be found. Both drafts and printed versions of individual poems and small groups of poems are present. The translations, which are arranged by language, include examples of Amichai's work in over fifteen different languages. The languages represented include: Arabic, Bengali, Chinese, Dutch, English, French, German, Greek, Gujarati, Hungarian, Italian, Polish, Romanian, Russian, Spanish, and Swedish. The final section of the subseries contains a number of adaptations of Amichai's poems set to music.
Printed versions of Amichai's poems, in Hebrew and in translation, can also be found among the clippings and periodicals in Series VI. Printed Materials.
The Speeches, Addresses, and Lectures subseries includes manuscript and printed transcripts of speeches, as well as notes and outlines in Amichai's hand. The majority are in Hebrew, but many English and German speeches are found here as well. In addition to giving readings, Amichai spoke at a number of literary and cultural events, such as conferences, festivals, book fairs, and award ceremonies, during the last two decades of his life. These public addresses cover such topics as literature, poetry, national identity, and the Israeli-Arab dispute. There are also memorial tributes for Yitzhak Rabin and others.
Notes and drafts for autobiographical statements, memorial tributes, and other short pieces of writing, including unidentified writings, can be found in the Other Writings subseries.
Series III, Writings of Others, housed in boxes 37-40, contains drafts and printed versions of work by others. The bulk of the writings in this series are about Amichai or Hebrew and Israeli literature and poetry more generally. Presumably most of these works, which include reviews and articles, as well as poems and theses, were sent to Amichai as a courtesy. Most of the work is in English, Hebrew, and German. The series is first arranged alphabetically by last name and then by title.
Series IV, Journals, housed in boxes 41-48, is arranged chronologically by date. The journals, written in Hebrew and German, date from 1954 to 1998, and include notes, diary entries, drafts and draft fragments for poems, and ideas for poems. Note: journals for the years 1964 to 1966 and 1993 are restricted.
Series V, Photographs, housed in boxes 49-51, is organized into four subseries: Yehuda Amichai, Events and Trips, Other People, and Other. There are portraits and snapshots of Yehuda Amichai alone and with others dating from 1929 to 1996. The series includes many photographs from literary events and reading tours, and of other writers: John Berryman, Breyten Breytenbach, J. M. Coetzee, Ted Hughes, Octavio Paz, Vasko Popa, Meir Shalev, Kazuko Shiraishi, Elizabeth Swados, and Andrei Voznesenski, among others.
There are approximately 200 cut film negatives corresponding to prints in the collection. The negatives were removed during processing and are stored separately in cold storage. A small number of photographic reference prints were made from negatives lacking corresponding prints.
Series VI, Printed Materials, housed in boxes 52-72, is organized into twelve subseries: Announcements; Awards; Bibliographies; Brochures, Pamphlets, and Promotional Material; Business Cards; Catalogs; Clippings; Conference and Event Material; Periodicals; and Other.
The printed materials in the collection document Amichai's public life from the 1950s to late 1990s. Announcements for readings and discussions, conference and event materials, and awards document public appearances and recognition. Conference and Event Material, for example, consists of printed ephemera relating to literary events attended by Amichai from the late 1960s to late 1990s.
The clippings and periodicals (i.e. journals, newspapers and newsletters) in the series contain work by and about Amichai. Here work by Amichai consists chiefly of printed versions of poems in Hebrew and in translation. Works about or mentioning Amichai range from brief references to literary analysis. Clippings and periodicals are both first arranged alphabetically by language. Languages represented in the clippings include: Chinese, Croation, Czech, Dutch, English, French, German, Hebrew, Hungarian, Italian, Japanese, Macedonian, Romanian, Russian, Spanish, and Swedish. The bulk of the clippings are stored in Oversize. Additional languages represented in the periodicals are Arabic, Georgian, Icelandic, and Serbian. Within each language, periodicals are arranged alphabetically by title. Periodicals are housed in boxes 59-71.
Series VII, Audio-Visual Material, housed in boxes 73-77, is organized into two subseries, Audio Recordings and Moving Image Material. There are original and commercial audio recordings of Amichai and others reading his work, and original and commercial video recordings of various events, including award ceremonies, interviews, and readings.
Series VIII, Personal Papers, housed in boxes 78-80, is arranged alphabetically by material type. There are addresses and phone numbers, artwork and drawings, biographical material, calendars, financial, legal, and medical records, lists of poems, and schedules and itineraries. Oversize material, housed in boxes 81-94, includes items from Series I-VIII. Restricted Fragile Papers are housed in boxes 97-104.
Authors, Hebrew -- 20th Century -- Archives; Hebrew literature -- 20th Century; Hebrew poetry -- 20th Century; Audiovisual materials; Clippings (information artifacts); Diaries; Photographic prints; Posters; Sound recordings; Video recordings; Authors; Albahari, David, 1948-; Allon, Yigal, 1918-1980; Amichai, Yehuda, 1924-2000; Ashbery, John, 1927-2017; Avidan, David; Banks, Lynne Reid, 1929-; Berryman, John, 1914-1972; Breytenbach, Breyten, 1939-; Celan, Paul, 1920-1970; Coetzee, J. M. (John Maxwell), 1940-; Dove, Rita, 1952-; Gregor-Dellin, Martin, 1926-1988; Hampl, Patricia, 1946-; Hollander, John, 1929-2013; Hughes, Ted, 1930-1998; Jong, Erica, 1940-; Kavanagh, Patrick, 1904-1967; Kollek, Teddy, 1911-2007; Nye, Naomi Shihab, 1952-; Olmert, Ehud, 1945-; Oz, Amos, 1939-; Ozick, Cynthia, 1928-; Pastan, Linda, 1932-; Paz, Octavio, 1914-1998; Peres, Shimon, 1923-2016; Popa, Vasko, 1922-1991; Rabin, Yitzhak, 1922-1995; Safdie, Moshe, 1938-; Sexton, Anne, 1928-1974; Shalev, Meir, 1948-; Shammas, Anton; Shazar, Zalman, 1889-1974; Shiraishi, Kazuko, 1931-; Sillitoe, Alan, 1928-; Sorescu, Marin, 1936-1996; Swados, Elizabeth, 1951-2016; Voznesenskiĭ, Andreĭ, 1933-2010
- Correspondence, 1944-1999; Series I; 5.63; (14 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is organized into two subseries: General Correspondence and Third Party Conrrespondence
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - 92nd Street Y (New York, N.Y.), 1982-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "A" General, 1974-1998, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - Abner Stein, 1990 Feb 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Abramson, Glenda, 1970-1999, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Academy of American Poets, 1986-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Actes Sud (Firm), 1985-1992, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - ACUM, 1965-1992 (Box 1, Folder 8-15)
    - ACUM, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
    - ACUM, 1995-1999, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
    - Adelaide Festival of Arts, 1992 Dec 10 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - After, Hanna Tadir, 1998 Mar 20 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Includes photocopies of poems
    - Agudat ha-sofrim ha-Ivrim (Palestine), 1968, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Aharoni, Ada, 1995 Nov 29 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Aigi, Gennadii, 1996 Jan 3 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Akhshav, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Akker, W. J. van den, 1994 May 18 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Albahari, David, 1981-1987 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Algal, Dalia, 1989-1998 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Alliance française de Jerusalem, 1992 Apr 23 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Allon, Yigal, 1970 Nov 15 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Almagor, Dan, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Alon, Rut; Alon, Azaria, 1981, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Aloni, Shulamit, 1992, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Alter, Robert, 1974-1991, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1986-1993 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - American Center of P.E.N., 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee, 1989 Nov 29 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - The American Poetry Review, 1983-1992 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - The American Voice, 1998 Feb 21 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Amichai, Chana, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Amichai, Emanuella, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Amichai, Ron, 1990 Aug 16 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Amnesty International Australia, 1991 Nov 1 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Amnesty International USA, 1986 Feb 5 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Apple, Max, 1985, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Argyriou, Astérios, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Ariel, 1990, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Arpaly, Boaz, 1987, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Arts Council of Ireland, 1987 Oct 12 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Artsi, Shelomoh, 1978 Sep 7 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Ashbery, John, 1988 Mar 24 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Asociación Internacional de Escritores Judíos en Lengua Hispana y Portuguesa, 1992 Mar 3 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Assa, Jonathan, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      Includes speech introducing Amichai
    - Augsburg Fortress (Publisher), 1996 Mar 26 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Avadenka, Lynne, 1993, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Avidan, David, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Avimor, Shimon, 1981 Nov 9 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Avi-Yonah, Yael, 1985 Aug 20 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Avni, Tzvi, 1971 Mar 23 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - "B" General, 1972-1999 (Box 2, Folder 60-61)
    - Balbuena, Monigue, 1999 Jun 6 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Banks, Lynne Reid, 1980 Jul 7 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Bar-Am, Micha, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Barbican Centre for Arts and Conferences, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Bar-Ilan University, 1982, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Bartlett, Paul Alexander, 1979 Oct 29 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Bartov, Reuven, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 68)
      Includes poems
    - Baskin, Leonard, 1992 Jun 20 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Bat-Adam, Michal, 1999 Oct 30 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Bayerischer Rundfunk, 1990, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Be. ha-s. ha-haklai Mikveh Yisrael, 1982, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, 1975-1995, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - BenShea, Noah, 1996 Dec 30 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Berliner Festpiele, 1991 Dec 6 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Bet lohame ha-getaot (Lohame ha-Getaot, Israel), 1997 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Betsalel (Academy), 1991 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Betten, Anne, 1995 Feb 13 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Biermann, Pamela, 1997 Sep 10 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Bloch, Chana, 1972-87 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Blumenthal, Michael, 1986 Dec, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - B'nai B'rith Anti-defamation League, 1991 Jun 19 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - B'nai B'rith International, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Bogatyrenko, Elena, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Böhmer, Paulus, 1991 Feb 1 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Bormenn, Alexander Von, 1995 Nov 24 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Bowmen, Steven B., 1994 Jan 24 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - [Brand, Jürgen?], 1983 Feb 8 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Bresnick, Martin, 1993 Dec 8 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Breytenbach, Breyten, 1997 Mar 29 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1967-1999 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - British Council, 1986 Sep 1 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Broza, Meir, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - BRT-Koor, 1978 Aug 16 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Budapest (Hungary), 1994 May 25 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Bureau of Jewish Education (Boston, Mass.), 1996 Jun 7 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - "C" General, 1968-1996 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - California Institute of the Arts, 1996 Oct 23 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - California. Resources Agency, 1971 Dec 17 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Callaghan, Barry, [1970?]-1993 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Campos, Harolda de, 1994 Apr (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Canada. Embassy (Israel), 1997 May 28 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Carl Hanser Verlag, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Cedering, Siv, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Celan, Paul, 1969 Nov 7 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Center for Contemporary Opera, 1995 Jul 7 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Center for Jewish Culture and Creativity, 1990-1998 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Centre international de poésie (Marseille), 1995 Dec 20 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Coffman, Lisa, 1994 Jul 25 (Box 3, Folder 110)
      Includes poem by Coffman
    - Cohen, Joseph, 1990 Dec 10 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Cohen, Nili, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Cohen, Zion, 1993 Feb 24 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - College of Charleston, 1991 Mar 25 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Columbia University, 1990 Mar 19 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Commentary, 1976 May 17 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Congregation Shaarey Zedek (Southfield, Mich.), 1976 Feb 18 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Coninck, Herman de, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Council for World Religions, 1987 Jun 9 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Cuddeback, Nicole, 1995 May 7 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Curzon, David, 1994 Mar 30 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Cutter, William, 1982 Sep 8 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - "D" General, 1975-1999, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 123-124)
    - Dasgupta, Mary Ann, 1974 Oct 6 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - [Datan?], Nancy, 1973 Jan 26 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - David, Y., 1982 Apr 28 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Davis, Cortney, 1995 Feb 2 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Degani, Assi, 1983 May 24 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Deganyah Alef (Israel), 1989 Jul 14 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Dekel, Shulamit, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Dettelbacher, [Werner?], 1972 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Deusch-Israelische Gesellschaft, 1987 Jan (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Deutsche Akademie für Sprache und Dichtang, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Deutsche Gesellschaft für Auswärtige Politik, 1992 Mar 26 (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Deutsche Welle, 1988 Aug 3 (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Dewey, Donald, 1967 Dec 29 (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Di Renzo editore, 1997, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Dial Press, 1981 Jan 27 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1977 Jan 7 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Dove, Rita, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 141)
      Includes copies of correspondence between Dove and International Poets' Festival, Jerusalem
    - Drury, John, 1995 Jan 30 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Duemer, Joseph, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - "E" General, 1979-1995 (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - Eckhard Elial, Michel, 1988 Jan 20 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Edelman, Lily, 1967 May 17 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Ehrlich, Abel, 1990 Apr 2 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Eisenreich, Herbert, 1973 Apr 30 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - Eked Publishing House, 1993 Mar 29 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Elias, Avi, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - El-Khalek, Abed, 1981-1983, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - Else Lasker-Schüler Gesellschaft, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Emory University, 1995 Jul 7 (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - Engel-Roux, Bernadette, 1992 May 17 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Eshel, Ruth, n.y. Nov 5 (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - European Cultural Center of Delphi, 1986 Feb 26 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - European Festival of Poetry (13th: 1991: Louvain, Belgium), 1991 Feb 14 (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - Evangelische Kommentare, 1988 Mar 9 (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - Evron, Ram, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - Eytan, Rachel, 1983 Apr 22 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - Exile, 1974-1992 (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - "F" General, 1973-1999, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - Falk, Marcia, 1989 May 15 (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1997 Nov 10 (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - Feinstein, Elaine, 1993 Oct 5 (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - Felstiner, John, 1989 Nov 30 (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - Festival Internacional de Poesía, 1982-1987 (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - Fischer Bucherei, 1965 Aug 19 (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - Flade, Roland, 1981-1997, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - Forcano, Manuel, 1992-1995, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - Forché, Carolyn, 1991 Sep 5 (Box 4, Folder 171)